Hello.
In this next lecture, I want to polish a few things about my game.
Currently, there's no out of bounds.
If I go play my play, a character can just jump off the edge of this world and continue falling forever.
In order to solve this, we're going to add an invisible collision which will block my character from
falling off the edge of the world.
If we go ad and select shapes and select cube.
Just go select and scale objects and scale this cube up.
And expand it in the Y and make it roughly this position and just place this at the edge of the world.
Then with the cube selected, go to details and look for hidden endgame and select this one actor hidden
in game and navigate play.
There'll be this invisible cube which will prevent my character from jumping off at the edge of the
world.
I'm just going to duplicate this cube and place it at the edge of the world here.
So first, control C and control V, and I'll paste this cube here.
The next thing we need to fix is our skeleton.
I noticed our skeleton can still rotate even when it dies.
So in order to fix this, if we open up our skeleton blueprint and go to the bit where we handle its
rotation, we're only going to handle the rotation of our Scantron if it's still alive.
So if we -- here and look for Branch and the condition for this branch is going to be whether
my skeleton is still alive.
So drag in that is dead variable.
And as long as this is false, then we'll update our skeletons rotation.
Just right click and break the link here on True and go compile and save.
Hello.
The next thing we're going to polish is my player character's wall slide system.
If I go play.
And I slide against this wall and I go up here.
There were two problems.
The first problem is my player character can sometimes rotate when they're sliding against the wall.
And the second problem is I play characters.
Full body doesn't have to be against the wall for my player character to slide.
So my player character can start walks.
I think when they're like, Here, we're only going to allow our player character to wall slide if they're
full body is along the wall.
So in order to fix this, if we close this and open up our player blueprint, go over to the event tip
where we handle our player character's rotation.
If our play character is ever on a wall, we're not going to allow them to rotate.
So if we just drag off here and look for a bunch.
And the condition of this branch is going to be we'll slide.
As long as this is false, then we will update my character's rotation.
However, if this is true, then we won't update our player character's rotation.
So right click on the true value and break the link here.
Next, in order to make it so that I can only slide if my character's full body is longer, we'll go
over to a bit where we had our war slide and drag off event hit and look for line trace by channel.
So we're going to do a line trace to make sure that my character's body is actually hitting a wall where
this is going to start.
Just right click and forget actor location.
And work.
This is going to end.
We're going to end it a couple of units in front of our player character.
So we just right click and forget.
Actor Forward Vector.
Track off the return value and look for multiply.
And just right click here and split the structure pin and then the x per value of 100.
And just track off the return value and look for ADD.
And just connect this here.
So we'll end the line.
Trace 100 units in front of our player character for the draw debug.
Just change this to for duration and just add a condition to this pin and connect the return value here
and go compile and you're going to visually see what I mean.
So if I go play and my player character slides will see the line trace and it'll hit green.
If I'm up against the wall, if I try and wall slide against the top of this wall, it's not going to
work because the line trace won't hear anything.
So with that, my player character is only going to slide if that full body is along the wall.
Hello.
The next thing I want to do is make it a bit smoother when my player character transitions between levels.
If I go to the end of my level one and I go play when my player reaches the end of this level, it's
a bit harsh when I just open the new level.
Instead, we're going to make our screen fade black and then open up the next level.
So if we go to the Widget blueprint and just right click and go user Interface widget Blueprint, I'll
select user widget.
And I'll just call this my fade widget Blueprint.
If we open up.
And in the palette book for a canvas panel and just drag this in.
Then in the palette, if we look for an image and just drag this in.
I'm going to anchor this across the whole of my screen and I'll make the offset value zero and all the
values.
Then I'm just going to change the color of this to be black.
And we'll go, Okay.
Then we're going to create an animation for this where it will initially be invisible and then we'll
fade in this black screen.
So if we go to animations and go create new animation and call this fade.
Then if we set this animation and go track and we want to track this image.
We want to track the rental opacity of this image.
So we go track and search rental opacity initially at 0 seconds.
We want this to have a render opacity of zero.
So I'm going to type on there here and add this new key.
Then around one second.
We want this to have a render opacity of one, and I'll just click add new key here.
So over the course of one second, we'll make my screen fade to black.
We can then go over to our graph.
And then construct, we can drag in our fade animation and we're just going to play this animation.
So a track of event construct and the full play animation and the animation is going to be the fade
animation and we can just go compile and save.
And now if I just select my level unlock blueprint, I'll open it up.
And before we actually open our level, I am going to drag up here and look for create widget.
The widget I am going to select is going to be the fade widget, and then we will add this to our viewport.
And our widget is one second and then we'll open up the next level.
So just go compile and go play.
So now when I beat my level, the screen will fade to black and then I'll take me to my next level.
So I think that's just a bit smoother.
You can play around if you want to.
For example, maybe add some text or make it a bit longer.
So maybe I'll make the animation 2 seconds and I'll take 2 seconds to open the level.
But I think that's just a bit smoother than just instantly opening up the next level.
I just want to showcase the system as a nice way of transitioning the player between levels.